<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!-- generator="WordPress/2.9.2" -->
<rss version="0.92">
<channel>
	<title>ExxonMobil&#039;s Perspectives Blog</title>
	<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 14:42:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>
	<language>en</language>
	
	<item>
		<title>What makes up the price of U.S. gasoline?</title>
		<description><![CDATA[I talked earlier this week about how crude oil prices have increased about 15 percent over the past year, which reflects a trend in rising commodity prices across the board in 2010. Not surprisingly, this means that gasoline prices are also up, because crude oil is the single-largest factor in determining the price at the pump in the U.S. But just how much does the price of crude impact U.S. gasoline prices?]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2011/01/13/what-makes-up-the-price-of-u-s-gasoline/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Fix education, fix the future</title>
		<description><![CDATA[Speaking at a conference hosted by The Academy of Medicine, Engineering and Science of Texas late last week, our chairman and CEO, Rex Tillerson, made an interesting statement that I think has implications for U.S. policy as we usher in a new Congress.
]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2011/01/12/fix-education-fix-the-future/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>What’s up with U.S. gasoline prices?</title>
		<description><![CDATA[Rising gasoline prices have been in the news recently, and there’s a lot of talk about why this is the case. Rising demand due to a global economic recovery, a lower value for the dollar, supply fundamentals – these are just a few of the potential factors that can drive up the price of crude oil, which in turn impacts the price of gasoline. Crude oil is one of a number of globally traded commodities like gold, corn, coffee and many others. ]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2011/01/10/whats-up-with-u-s-gasoline-prices/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>A specific – not systemic – failure</title>
		<description><![CDATA[The release yesterday of findings by the presidential commission on the BP-Deepwater Horizon accident has helped give us a fuller picture of what happened in the tragic Gulf of Mexico blowout, explosion and oil spill. The report concluded that the disaster was avoidable and resulted from a specific series of management failures on the part of the companies involved.]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2011/01/06/a-specific-not-systemic-failure/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. EIA forecasts growing domestic natural gas supplies – and Americans will benefit</title>
		<description><![CDATA[When the U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA) released its Annual Energy Outlook 2011 last week, growing U.S. shale gas production was the major headline. The upswing of natural gas in general is good news for several reasons: it's a cleaner-burning fuel for power generation, resulting in up to 60 percent less carbon dioxide emissions than coal; the abundance of domestic gas supplies helps strengthen U.S. energy security; and growing gas production means more jobs and economic activity in states across the U.S. But if you go back only five or 10 years, few would have been talking about these benefits of domestic supplies of natural gas. ]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2010/12/20/u-s-eia-forecasts-growing-domestic-natural-gas-supplies/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Gaining ground on malaria</title>
		<description><![CDATA[I am excited to report that today, we have more proof that the global effort to eradicate malaria is working. The World Malaria Report 2010, released today by the World Health Organization (WHO), shows a 10-percent drop in global malaria deaths between 2008 and 2009; in more than 11 African countries, confirmed malaria cases and deaths have declined by almost 50 percent in recent years.]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2010/12/14/gaining-ground-on-malaria/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>ExxonMobil is a leading U.S. taxpayer</title>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, the false claim that ExxonMobil paid “zero taxes in 2009” made another appearance in the political arena. The facts don’t support this claim, but for many it proves too good to pass up when engaging in political theater. Claims that ExxonMobil did not pay taxes in 2009 are just plain incorrect. The myth started with a misreading of our 2009 10-K filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, and it’s now being perpetuated for all kinds of reasons. So, let me set the record straight.]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2010/12/14/exxonmobil-is-a-leading-u-s-taxpayer/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. jobs from Canadian energy</title>
		<description><![CDATA[As the 111th Congress wraps up its business, it’s time to look ahead – to a new year and, hopefully, to renewed economic opportunities and job growth for our economy. So, I thought I’d spend a little time talking about the opportunity to create hundreds of thousands of U.S. jobs by partnering with our neighbor to the north. Canada not only supplies the largest portion of U.S. oil imports, but its oil sands production also represents a huge opportunity for American job growth. ]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2010/12/13/u-s-jobs-from-canadian-energy/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>A trillion-dollar missed opportunity &#8211; enough to pay U.S. deficit</title>
		<description><![CDATA[On the heels of the Administration’s recent decision to place a de facto moratorium on offshore drilling in the eastern Gulf of Mexico and the Atlantic, we asked readers of today’s Wall Street Journal if they knew how much that decision might cost in terms of lost government revenue.]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2010/12/06/a-trillion-dollar-missed-opportunity-enough-to-pay-u-s-deficit/</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Is the world running out of oil?</title>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently, Newsweek invited its Twitter followers to suggest topics to discuss here on this blog. We had a great response and a lot of ideas. But I noticed that one theme kept coming up: Is the world running out of oil? This is a legitimate question, and one that those of us at ExxonMobil hear frequently; so, I'd like to address it.]]></description>
		<link>http://www.exxonmobilperspectives.com/2010/12/03/is-the-world-running-out-of-oil/</link>
			</item>
</channel>
</rss>
